<Publish>
	<!--Id must be set in order to update existed mod. it is not required for publishing mod for the first time-->
	<ModId Value="77397" />
	<!--Name of the mod to display to players-->
	<DisplayName Value="Land Value Overhaul" />
	<!--Short description of the mod-->
	<ShortDescription Value="Overhaul on the game's land value, rent and building upgrade mechanisms." />
	<!--Long description of the mod. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<!--LongDescription Value="Overhaul on the game's land value, rent & building upgrade mechanisms." /-->
	<LongDescription>Overhaul on the game's land value, rent and building upgrade mechanisms.

## Why needed?

The vanilla land value system, along with the rent and building upgrade system, are designed without careful thoughts and lack sufficient testing and polishing, no matter before or after the game update 1.1.0. Before 1.1.0, the market-based land value system has led to:

* High-density residents, even rich and educated, are struggling to pay their rents. Land value of these estates could climb to 1,200,000$.
* Commercial zones are constantly yielding "Not enough customer" warnings, even when they are built in reasonable locations.
* Low-density residential buildings are dying simply because they share the same road with office/high-density residential buildings.
* The land value is instantly spreading from city centers to remote and less-urbanized regions along major roads.
* The city's average land value is unusually high and still climbing above, let's say, 2,000,000$.

The 1.1.0 update, however, brutely binds the land value with merely five factors: transportation, healthcare, education, police, and commercial coverages. it is still reported that:

* The low-density high-rent issue persists.
* Even higher rent for commercial zones, causing more "Not enough customer" warnings.
* Land value and rent for high-density residential areas are too low to complement their upkeep.
* The land value tooltip system is lying on the real land value, causing confusion.

This mod makes a **thorough overhaul** on the game's **land value update mechanism**, the associated **building upgrade mechanism** along with some extra small fix. Please see GitHub page for details and full descriptions of the modifications this mod made to vanilla systems. The below list is only a short overview.

## Feature

* Implemented a soft market-based land value(LV) update mechanism, which is the combination of the LV system in LandValueOverhaul 1.4.3(See the github page for details), and the vanilla 1.1.0 LV system. This system is designed to be numerically stable and self-balancing. It adjusts itself to:
* Make the LV reasonable, realistic and dynamic.
* Make the corresponding rent comfortable for most renters(instead of 50%).
* Make building upgrade more smooth and reduce abandoned buildings.
* The LV will stablizes at a level that is determined by the market(most acceptable by nearby property renters). But property renters that are not willing to pay high rent are now **favored** in the land value update mechanism, ensuring the **majority** of renters along a road edge, instead of 50% of them, can afford their rents.
* Land value will fade in a **shorter** distance(200 instead of 2000, configurable), also in a **slower** speed(0.001 instead of 0.01, configurable), resulting in a more cliffy land value distribution, which is more realistic.
* Building upkeep will increase **linearly** with building level, instead of exponentially. This effectively reduces the rent, causing less high-rent warnings.
* Building upgrade cost will increase **slower** with building level, but still exponentially. This effectively speeds up the building upgrade, making it easier for high-density residentials getting to level 5.
* Area size of low density residential properties will be considered **square root of the area size** in land-value-related computations, to avoid extremely high per-family rent for low-density residentials.
* Garbage fee will **no longer decrease** the building upgrade progress.
* The land value tooltip system now **correctly displays the real land value**.
		
## Known Issues

* Currently NOT BepInEx compatible, will support soon.

## Important Notes

* Bankrupting stores and companies are still most likely to yield high-rent warnings, since they cannot pay anything.
* The overall system is BETA and still need more testing. FEEDBACKS are most welcomed(via Github issues).
* The land-value-related effect of this mod is **not instantly observable**. It takes time (sometimes quite a lot) to adapt everything to the new mechanisms. The land value will require multiple in-game days to re-stablize.
* The building-related effect of this mod is **instantly observable**. Massive floods of building upgrade are possible when loading existing save games played without this mod.
* The configurable options are applied only once, during the mod initialization. For new setting to take effect, you need to **restart the game**.
* This mod affects save games, as it modifies the land value. **Backup your save before installing!**
* This mod affects the game's pop simulation, which would possibly result in unexpected and unrelated behaviors (e.g. Suddenly everyone wants to move into the city).
* This mod **conflicts** with any mod that makes changes to land-value-related systems.
		
## Technical

* Modified systems: BuildingUpkeepSystem, LandValueSystem, PropertyRenterSystem, RentAdjustSystem, LandValueTooltipSystem.
	</LongDescription>
	<!--Thumbnail-->
	<Thumbnail Value="Properties/Thumbnail.png" />
	<!--Screenshot, can be set multiple times-->
	<Screenshot Value="docs/lvdistribution1.png" />
	<Screenshot Value="docs/lvdistribution2.png" />
	<!--Tag, can be set multiple times-->
	<Tag Value="Code Mod" />
	<!--Link to the forum post where the mod can be discussed-->
	<ForumLink Value="" />
	<!--Version of the mod-->
	<ModVersion Value="1.5.4" />
	<!--Recommended version of the base game to use the mod-->
	<GameVersion Value="1.1.*" />
	<!--Dependency for the mod, can be set multiple times-->
	<Dependency Id="" />
	<!--Change log for new version. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<ChangeLog>
v1.5.4
* Rewrite the building upkeep modification, so that it is guaranteed to be correctly loaded.
	</ChangeLog>
	<!--External link. supported types are discord, github, youtube, twitch, x, paypal, patreon-->
	<ExternalLink Type="github" Url="https://github.com/Jimmyokok/LandValueOverhaul" />
</Publish>
